Finding Aid for Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination Records 1978-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination Records
1978-1997
Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination.
Environmental group formed in 1978 by landowners in Clare County, Michigan in resistance to government plan to use pesticide to control gypsy moth population. The organization has since broadened its focus to include other environmental issues such as solid waste management, wetlands protection, the use of herbicides, concerns about toxic waste, and problems of pollution in Michigan. Series in this record group include organizational files, Eco Conferences, subject files, and related organizations. Organizational files includes minutes, newsletters, reports, correspondence, grant proposals, and other materials relating to the work of the organization. The Eco Conferences series documents annual conference bringing together speakers to lead talks and workshops. This series includes annual planning files and audiocassettes and videocassettes of the conferences. Subject files contains correspondence, reports, background information, and other information on environmental issues. Related organizations consists of files on other Michigan and local environmental groups.
0289 Bn 2
11.75 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The record group (Donor No. 9133 ) was received in October 2001.
The record group is open for research.
The environmental group Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination (CACC) was formed in 1978 by landowners in Clare County, Michigan in resistance to a State Department of Agriculture plan to control the gypsy moth population with a program of spraying the pesticide Dimilin. Since its founding, CACC has taken an interest in a wide range of environmental topics beyond the scope of gypsy moth spraying -- including, solid waste, pollution, herbicides, wetlands protection, and toxic waste. The organization changed its name in 1982 from Citizens Against Chemical Contaminants to reflect this broadened scope.
Ann Hunt, a founding member of CACC, served as Executive Director from 1983 to 1997, the only paid employee of the organization. In this role, she was responsible for the day-to-day operation of the organization and developed it into a prominent organization within the state of Michigan. With a paid staff member, CACC was able to maintain a broad correspondence with other environmental organizations and individuals. Five other Michigan environmental organizations became CACC-affiliated chapters over the years.
CACC since 1983 sponsored an annual Backyard Eco Conference, bringing together a variety of speakers from around the country to lead talks and workshops, educating participants on a wide variety of environmental issues. CACC maintained a resource library for staff and public information, printed a monthly newsletter with a distribution of over 500, and served in advisory capacities on many state environmental issues.
As a non-profit organization, funding was often tight, particularly in years immediately after its establishment. Funding largely came from the operation of a food concession at an annual music festival (Wheatland). Other funding was made available from annual membership dues, personal donations, and grant awards.
CACC has been a member of the Michigan Environmental Council (MEC), a coalition of Michigan environmental groups, since the mid-1980s; Ann Hunt was a member of the MEC Board of Directors, serving as treasurer from 1988 to 1990, and as chair of the board from 1990 to 1992. Hunt also served on the steering committee of the National Citizens Network on Oil and Gas Wastes and the Environmental Defense Fund's Pollution Prevention Alliance, and as an at-large member of the Board of Directors of Great Lakes United from 1992 to 1993. Hunt also served on the Governor's Cabinet Council on Environmental Protection's Pesticide Advisory Committee. Much of Hunt's work in these areas is documented in the collection.
The Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination record group provides an in-depth look at the life of a very active and influential Michigan environmental organization, for a period of nearly two decades -- from 1978 to 1997. While describing in particular the activities of one individual organization, the collection also lends itself to research about environmental issues and Michigan environmental organizations in general. The collection is arranged into four record series: Organizational Files, Eco Conferences, Subject Files, and Related Organizations.
Subjects:
Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination.; Green movement--Michigan.; Clare County (Mich.); Environmental protection--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan--Clare County.; Gypsy moth--Control--Environmental aspects--Michigan.; Gypsy moth--Control--Michigan.; Hazardous waste--Environmental aspects--Michigan.; Michigan Environmental Council.; Pesticides policy--Michigan.; Water quality--Michigan.; Wetland conservation--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Green movement--Michigan.
Subjects--Sound Recordings
Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination.; Gypsy moth--Control--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan.
Genre/Form:
Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Organizational Files
  The Organizational Files (3.5 linear feet) document the daily life of the organization. Meeting minutes describe the issues addressed by CACC and the activities of the organization; the newsletters document similar topics, in addition to covering general environmental issues of a regional and national scope. The Contractor/Executive Director reports provide in-depth information on the day-to day work of Ann Hunt. The details of these monthly reports to CACC's board include contacts made by phone and mail, progress on projects and grant applications, and meetings attended. An extensive correspondence file paints a picture of the far-reaching influence that CACC held.
  - History (Box 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation and Amendments, 1978-1994 (Box 1)
  - By-laws, 1986-1991 (Box 1)
  - CACC Facts (Box 1)
  - Chapters
    - Chapter Agreement Forms, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Clean Air, Please!, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
    - Citizens League for Environmental Action and Responsibility (CLEAR), 1990-1996 (Box 1)
    - Huron Environmental Activist League (HEAL), 1992-1996 (Box 1)
    - International Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination (Inter-ACC), 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Tri-County Residents for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination (TRACC)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1994; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Grant Workshop, 1991 (Box 1)
      - TRACC Grants, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Committees
    - Ad hoc Personnel Committee (Box 1)
    - Committee to Support the Bond, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Education Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Environmental Action Committee, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Nuclear Weapons Freeze Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Steering Committee, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Contractor/Executive Director Reports, 1983-1997; 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1980; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1997; 22 folders (Box 2)
  - Employment Contracts, 1983-1984; 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Fundraising
    - Miscellaneous Efforts, 1982-1996 (Box 3)
    - Wheatland
      - Correspondence, 1982-1995 (Box 3)
  - Governor's Conference and Ann Hunt (videocassette), circa 1991; 1 videotapes (Box 3)
  - Grant Proposals
    - Alton Jones Foundation, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Beldon Fund, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - Campaign for Human Development, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - C.S. Mott Foundation, 1984-1992 (Box 3)
    - Clean Michigan Fund, 1987; 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Citizens' Resistance at Fermi 2 (CRAFT), 1994 (Box 3)
    - Eco 1984 Videotaping Proposal (Box 3)
    - Environmental Support Center, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - Funding Exchange, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
    - Grassroots Leadership Development Project, 1994-1995
      - Advisory Reports (Box 3)
      - Program and Evaluation (Box 3)
      - Proposal and Publicity (Box 3)
      - Survey and Responses (Box 3)
      - Video (Box 3)
    - Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Harder Foundation, 1984-1996 (Box 3)
    - Joyce Foundation, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Lakes Area Community Association, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Council for the Arts, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Environmental Council
      - Land Use Initiative, circa 1992 (Box 3)
      - Riparian Stewardship Project, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Mott Leadership Development Proposal, 1989 (Box 3)
    - National Coalition Against the Misuse of Pesticides
      - Aquatic Weed Control Project, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
      - Pesticide Alternatives Project, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
    - Ottinger Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - Pesticide Reduction Activities in the Great Lakes, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Pew Charitable Trusts, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Reed Foundation, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Ruth Mott Fund, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Saginaw Bay National Watershed Initiative, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Tides Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Meetings
    - Annual Meetings, 1985-1997; 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 1990-1997; 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Regular Meetings, 1982-1989; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Newsletters, 1978-1999; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Property Transfer, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - Radio Underwriting, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Retreat, 1992; 1996 (Box 4)
  - Tax Filings, 1978-1997 (Box 4)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1982-1991 (Box 4)
- Eco Conferences
  The Eco Conferences series (1.5 linear feet) provides details about the annual environmental education conference CACC sponsored. Annual files contain programs outlining presenters and topics discussed, as well as ideas for other panels, children's educational activities, and outreach. Videocassettes and audio cassettes within the series provide audio/visual perspective.
  - Annual Files, 1983-1996; 14 folders (Box 4)
  - Audiocassettes, 1983; 1991; 30 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Videocassettes
    - Eco, 1984; 3 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1987; 5 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1988; 6 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1989; 6 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1990; 1 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1991; 4 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1992; 5 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, 1994; 3 videotapes (Box 5)
    - Eco, circa 1995; 1 videotapes (Box 5)
- Subject Files
  The third series, Subject Files (5 linear feet), contains information on various environmental topics of interest to CACC and provides a general background on contemporary environmental issues in Michigan and at a national level. Correspondence and position statements relating to some of these topics describe CACC's perspective on and involvement in these areas of interest. Of particular note are the Gypsy Moth files, describing the issues that led to CACC's establishment, files on Dow Chemical Company, and the Michigan-focused PBB controversy.
  - Air Pollution
    - Air Quality, 1987-1994 (Box 6)
    - Clean Air Act, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Brine Disposal -- Clare County
    - Application Records, 1987; 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1986; 1993-1996 (Box 6)
    - Management Plans, 1981-1987 (Box 6)
    - Mid-Michigan Trucking Violations, 1986; 1991-1993 (Box 6)
    - Task Force Recommendations, 1980; 1990; 1994 (Box 6)
  - Canada, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Chemicals
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
    - Greenpeace Midland Michigan Chlorine Public Meeting, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Polybromated Biphenyl (PBB), 1983 (Box 6)
  - Department of Natural Resources
    - Correspondence, 1984-1994 (Box 6)
    - Reorganization, 1987-1988; 1991-1994 (Box 6)
  - Dow Chemical
    - Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 6)
    - NPDES Permit and Administrative Consent Order, 1997 (Box 6)
    - Project XL, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Revetment Groundwater Interception System (RGIS) Failure and Request for Variance, 1995-1997 (Box 6)
  - Drain Code Revision, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Dupont, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Energy
    - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 6)
    - Michigan Energy Options Study, 1985-1988 (Box 6)
    - Michigan Public Service Commission, 1990-1995 (Box 6)
    - Michigan Wood Energy Development Plan, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - Wood Fired Power Plants, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Fairness in Broadcasting Act, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, 1986-1987 (Box 6)
  - Food Safety Council
    - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 6)
    - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
    - Membership (Box 6)
    - Program Outline, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Survey on Consumer and Farmer Attitudes on Food Safety, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Gypsy Moth
    - Annual file on gypsy moth, 1985-1994; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Audio cassettes, 1978; 1990; 7 audiocassettes (Box 6)
    - Clippings File (Box 6)
    - County Suppression Programs
      - Clare County, 1978; 1987-1989; 4 folders (Box 6)
      - Iosco County, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Menominee County, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Midland County, 1988 (Box 6)
      - Montcalm County, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Department of Natural Resources Region II Spraying Information, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Litigation
      - Litigation, 1978-1981; 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 7)
      - Litigation -- MDA Plans, 1989 (Box 7)
      - Spraying Notifications, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Department of Agriculture
      - Background Information, 1978-1981 (Box 7)
      - Joint meetings, 1978 (Box 7)
      - Pennsylvania Trip, 1978 (Box 7)
    - National Gypsy Moth Review Meeting, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Position Statement and Background Information (Box 7)
    - Reports
      - Gypsy Moth: A Workbook About Michigan's Newest Insect, circa 1986 (Box 7)
      - Gypsy Moth Defoliation Report, 1987 (Box 7)
      - Gypsy Moth Scientific Review Panel Report, 1991 (Box 7)
      - Gypsy Moth Trapping Data, 1987 (Box 7)
      - Treatment Applications, 1990 (Box 7)
    - State Management Plans, 1978-1984; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Suppression Means
      - Aerial Applicators, 1989 (Box 7)
      - Insecticides, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Hazardous Wastes
    - Deep Well Injection
      - Class I Underground Injection Control (UIC) Wells, 1987-1994 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence and Comments, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
      - Dow Brine System, 1985 (Box 7)
      - Gelman Science Permit, 1984-1988; 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Kaiser-Francis Oil Company Permit, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
    - Incineration
      - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
      - LaFarge Toxic Incinerator, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Landfills
      - Act 64 Site Review Board Hazardous Waste Management Planning Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
      - Augusta Township Toxic Waste Facility, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
      - PCB Disposal -- Allen Park Clay Mine Landfill, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
    - Statistics, 1982-1984 (Box 7)
    - Toxic Substances Control Commission, 1984-1988 (Box 7)
  - Health
    - Families for Environmental Health Awareness, 1990-1993 (Box 7)
    - Great Lakes Health Banner Coalition, 1991-1993
      - Correspondence and Materials (Box 7)
    - Michigan Center for Rural Health, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Comparative Risks Analysis Project, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Environmental Health Coalition, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - Midland County Birth Defects, 1983-1986 (Box 7)
    - Organization for the Advancement of Environmental Health, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Public Interest Research Group in Michigan (PIGRIM), Report on the Cancer Connection, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Incineration
    - Dow Chemical Dioxin-Burning Incinerator Litigation, 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Genesee Power Plant, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Incinerator Ash Regulation, 1988-1992 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Incinerator Coalition, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Land Use
    - Great Lakes Island Transfer, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Land Use Institute, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Subdivision Control Act Revisions, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Legislation
    - Pesticide Prior Notification (SB 65), 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - Polluter Pays Bill (HB 5878; SB 375), 1990 (Box 7)
    - Safe Drinking Water Bill (HR 3200), 1982-1992 (Box 7)
    - School Nature Study Areas (HB 5130), 1985-1987 (Box 7)
  - Military/Defense
    - Camp Grayling National Guard Training Facility, 1990-1994 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Nuclear Weapons Freeze (Proposal E), 1982-1983 (Box 8)
    - Military Toxics, 1985-1991 (Box 8)
    - Stop Project ELF (Extremely Low Frequency), 1980-1985; 1994 (Box 8)
    - Wurtsmith Air Force Base, 1991-1993 (Box 8)
  - Natural Resources and Environmental Code Commission, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Natural Resources Trust Fund, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Nuclear Waste
    - Big Rock Point Nuclear Power Plant, 1989-1995 (Box 8)
    - Citizens Resistance at Fermi II (CRAFT), 1986; 1994-1995 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Box 8)
    - Hillsdale Organization for the Preservation of the Environment (HOPE), 1988-1989 (Box 8)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste, 1987-1995 (Box 8)
    - Midland Nuclear Power Plant, circa 1979 (Box 8)
    - Palisades Nuclear Plant, 1988-1994 (Box 8)
    - Upper Peninsula (UPEC) Nuclear Waste Info Series, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Oil and Gas
    - Act 61 -- Michigan Oil and Gas Act
      - Comments and Recommendations on Proposed Changes, 1992 (Box 8)
      - Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 8)
      - Hazardous Substance Definition, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
      - Naturally Occurring Radioactive Materials (NORM) and Well Plugging, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - State-Owned Minerals, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Biosphere and BIOAC Technologies, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Birmingham Gun Club Drill Site, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Citizens for Responsible Oil and Gas Development, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1996; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Interstate Oil and Gas Compact Commission, Naturally Occurring Radioactive Materials Subcommittee, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Jordan River Valley Drilling Proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Energy Reform Coalition
      - Correspondence, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Public Meeting, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Environmental Council Mini-Grant-Oil and Gas Development, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Environmental Council, Oil and Gas Workgroup, 1991-1994 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Oil and Gas Association Meeting, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Oil and Gas Regulation, 1988-1991 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Oil and Gas Task Force, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Mineral Exploration, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
    - National Citizens Network on Oil and Gas Wastes
      - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
      - Meetings and Agendas, 1990-1992 (Box 8)
    - Nordhouse Dunes Mining, 1987; 1991-1995 (Box 8)
    - Northwoods Watershed Project, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Northern Michigan Oil and Gas Coalition, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Post-production Costs Agreement, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Presque Isle County Oil and Gas Drilling, 1988-1994 (Box 8)
    - Terra Energy Drilling, 1991; 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Utility Deregulation, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Pesticides and Herbicides
    - 2, 4-D Litigation, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Alternatives, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1997 (Box 8)
    - DDT Contamination, 1987-1996 (Box 8)
    - Herbicide Drift, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Integrated Pest Management, 1994-1996 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Department of Agriculture -- Pesticide and Plant Pest Management Division, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Pesticide Network, 1986-1989 (Box 9)
    - Mosquito Abatement
      - Bay County Mosquito Control (Box 9)
      - Michigan Mosquito Control Association, 1985-1987 (Box 9)
      - Michigan Pest Control Bill (HB 4761), 1990 (Box 9)
      - Saginaw County Mosquito Abatement Commission, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
    - Organic Certification Standards, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Pesticides: Benefits, Risks and Alternatives Conference, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Pesticide Control Work Group, 1986-1988 (Box 9)
    - Strategy for Improved Pesticide Management, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Stroz Services Inc., 1986-1995; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Termiticides, 1985-1986; 1992 (Box 9)
    - Tordon, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Trespass, 1986-1988 (Box 9)
  - Pollution Legislation
    - Michigan Environmental Response Act (Act 307), 1989-1995 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Polluter Pays Legislation (SB 375, HB 4596 and 4597), 1989-1990; 1995 (Box 9)
  - Rails to Trails, 1988-1993 (Box 9)
  - Recycling
    - Composting, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box 9)
    - Methane Recovery, 1994 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Recycling Coalition Conference, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Unclaimed Bottle Deposits Initiative, 1988-1990 (Box 9)
    - Plastics, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Recycle! Marquette, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Used Motor Oil Recycling, 1980-1990 (Box 9)
    - Waste Oil Action, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
  - Right-to-Know, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Solid Waste
    - Carleton Farms Landfill, Wayne County, 1993-1995 (Box 9)
    - CACC Position Paper on Solid Waste, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Clare County Solid Waste
      - Clare County Landfill
        - Establishment, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
        - Legal complaint, 1990 (Box 9)
      - Management Plan
        - Correspondence, 1987-1992; 2 folders (Box 9)
        - Original Plan, 1983 (Box 9)
        - Update, 1988; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Planning Committee, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Reciprocity Letters, 1988-1992 (Box 10)
      - Solid Waste Work Plan, 1981 (Box 10)
      - Surrey Township Transfer Facility, 1993 (Box 10)
      - Work Plan for Solid Waste Management Planning, 1992-1993 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 10)
    - Gladwin County Solid Waste Management Plan, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Herrguth Landfill, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Hersey Township Solid Waste Ordinance, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Hillsdale County Landfill, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
    - Livingston County -- North Ore Creek Site Proposal, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Macomb County Solid Waste Planning Litigation, 1987-1989 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Solid Waste Strategy, 1988-1989 (Box 10)
    - North Central Michigan Resource Recovery Center, Roscommon County, circa 1991 (Box 10)
    - Reuter Resource Recovery System, Osceola County, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
    - Richmond Township Landfill, Osceola County, 1987-1992; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Waste Management Incorporated Antitrust Suit, 1991 (Box 10)
    - Waterford Hills Landfill, Oakland County, 1990-1991 (Box 10)
    - Wayne County Solid Waste Management Plan, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Superfund Sites
    - Cadillac Cleanup (SB 172), 1991 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Superfund Site Descriptions, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Waste Reduction
    - Michigan Waste Reduction Research Strategy, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, 1984-1992 (Box 10)
  - Water Quality
    - Clare County Water Pollution, 1984-1987 (Box 10)
    - Clean Water Action -- Vote Environment Committee, 1996 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1997 (Box 10)
    - Dow Discharge Permit, 1984-1986; 1995 (Box 10)
    - Great Lakes Initiative, 1991-1996; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Alliance, 1991-1995 (Box 10)
    - Great Lakes Water Pollution, 1985-1997 (Box 10)
    - Groundwater Contamination Strategies for Citizens, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Groundwater Management Strategy for Michigan, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
    - Groundwater Networking Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
    - Impacts of Golf Courses on Groundwater and Surface Water, 1991 (Box 10)
    - International Joint Commission, 1984-1993
      - Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Box 10)
    - Lake Superior Network, 1990; 1994-1995 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Fish Advisories (HB 4206), 1997 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Water Quality Standards, Rule 57, 1985 (Box 10)
    - Monitoring Proposal for PPG Industries, 1984-1987 (Box 10)
    - Safe Drinking Water Act, 1995-1996 (Box 10)